Is this everybody?
Okay. In full disclosure,
this entire app and this whole handout was made with AI.
So if there's something on it that sounds weird or doesn't correlate,
just know everything we're doing right now is in
rough draft form and we're all in learning mode.
So the first thing I want you to do though is actually go to
the backside and at the very bottom it says,
Carmel cell phone. Do you guys have your cell phones with you?
If you could pull it out and send me a text and include your first and last name,
so I know who the text is coming from.
Then if you could tell me how your schedule looks for the week.
Because this week was the first week in
BLP history that we have done 100 percent AI scheduling.
But the problem is, it's actually pretty good.
It should be pretty good.
But all the information that the AI is working with is not yet accurate.
That's what we're going to learn about today.
Then all of you are going to help us get all of the tracks,
phases, store all of the information accurate.
Then the AI scheduling will become more and more accurate each week as we train it.
But I'm just curious with the limited information that it has,
because it has been studying your Friday reports and trying to do its best guess.
Send me a text telling me in percentage like 80 percent,
20 percent, how accurate does your schedule look like?
If it looks like Brigham did it,
then put 100 percent.
If it looks like a drunk AI from a different store did it,
then put five percent or anywhere in between.
Then you could add any notes if you want.
It was almost right, but it assigned me a piano that was already completed,
so I moved on to the next thing.
Just any feedback of what it looks like would be helpful.
Then I'll have everybody's text too,
so I can double-check that because we're
training the AI to also be able to send you texts and updates.
On September 1st, we're going to convert over the ISOLVE clock in,
you'll be able to clock in on the map.
Then starting, I think is it working,
the clocking into the pianos? I think that's working.
Starting today after this meeting,
you'll be able to clock in and out of your pianos on the store map.
Starting September 1st, you'll be able to clock in for your payroll hours here.
But then, so you know we have a policy,
we try not to do overtime unless it's approved ahead of time.
Instead of Melissa keeping an eye on that,
are you keeping an eye on that?
It'll send you a text like,
two hours left and then you're done for the week or something like that.
Right now, everything is in innovation invention mode.
All ideas are welcome and helpful.
The most helpful thing you can do right now as we roll this out and you all start
playing with it today is to help us find the glitches and problems,
not just with the actual feature,
but just with the technology itself.
Because it might be a great feature,
but not quite working right.
Or not quite working right on your phones.
We are ordering Chromebooks so that in the shop,
you'll be able to use this app on one of these instead of your phones,
which should make it a lot easier.
But, yeah.
Much easier. Don't get discouraged today doing it on a phone.
It's much, much easier on a Chromebook.
It feels clunky, but it's, yeah, we'll get there.
Yeah. We're going to have a Chromebook arm that's in each table,
rebuilding station that you can move to either side,
and then also a few that will roam around to be free.
If you're working on a panel like the square grand right now,
that's not at a station.
But you can always use your phones as well.
Plus, somewhere on here, is there a phone number?
Texting, number six.
Also texting, is the phone number on there that you text to, or I didn't put it?
Mark, do you know that number?
I think I sent it to you.
I think it's number six,
but I didn't put the number, did I?
It's on the back, so you can text below and send it to the one on the front.
Oh, yeah. Towards the bottom.
Above the green print.
That cell phone number,
you should be able to text to that as well,
and the green print gives you examples.
So if you want to, you can,
so eventually, you'll be able to use your phone, a Chromebook,
or I guess also your phone, but just send a text.
But if you send a text,
I'm not going to tell you these examples, just read them.
They're self-explanatory, but make sure you include the serial number.
On your phone, if you put in a wrong serial number,
though, it might be more risky,
whereas on the store map,
if you put in a wrong serial number,
it's less likely to accept it.
We've been, the new managers,
we have been making some pre-suggestions.
One of them was to make it so you can't put in a wrong spot number,
just won't accept it.
Should we just get started? If you want to,
you could sign in right now with Google if you haven't.
As you start trying some of these things on your own,
and on the back, there's three habits that matter most.
It would be number 10 if it had a number.
Those are the first things you can try today after this training,
and if while you're trying them, it doesn't work,
that would be a success and a victory because we will have quickly found
something to improve in our new custom software that we're all learning together.
The most helpful thing you can do is feel celebratory,
that you're the one who found a glitch,
and then take a screenshot,
and you see the light bulb?
It's like, the light bulb.
You can suggest an improvement.
An edit would be like,
I found a glitch with the search feature.
So take a screenshot of it.
You can attach your screenshot and then send it.
If the screenshot is self-explanatory, just send it.
If it's not, maybe add a phrase.
Right now, these are coming to me.
Eventually, we're going to have Mark help as well,
so you don't have to wait for me.
Things tend to get clogged when they rely on me.
Then there's the idea button.
I think you guys are going to have a lot of ideas as you start working with this.
You're going to wish it could do something else.
I have wished one million wishes over the last 25 years of being an entrepreneur,
of what I wished the software would do,
because we would pay so much for this software,
and then it didn't do what we wanted it to do.
We had to tweak it to be a piano store software when it was really meant for a finance company.
But guess what? With AI,
we can literally make all of our wishes come true immediately.
Any idea you have or whatever you want it to do,
I can't promise that we'll implement every single idea,
but we'll try to.
Most of them, the more ideas we have, the better.
If you send in a few ideas that don't happen,
that's great too, because it means we're getting a high volume of ideas.
If you have that thought like,
I wish it could do this,
hit the light bulb and send what you wish it could do,
and likely by the next day or next week, it will do that.
You'll get a text back alerting you that that feature is live.
So signing in and out,
I think that's self-explanatory.
So for finding a piano,
there's different ways to find a piano.
You can type in the serial number at the top here,
and then it starts auto-loading.
So you could search by year or make or model.
If you don't know the serial number and you don't want to go look,
but you know that you're working on an Emerson,
you start typing in Emerson,
and it'll bring up all the Emersons,
and then you can say, oh yeah,
I recognize it's that one, it's this one.
Maybe it is or maybe it's not.
But you can also scan the shop tag.
Have you seen the new shop tags around?
They should be taped.
We used to tape them only on the right side,
now they should be taped on the right and the left.
We did also a super speedy AI-created full set of shop tags to print the new version.
So I'd say they're probably like 60 percent useful,
because we just told it to search the piano log and all the files and everything it knew,
and print a whole set.
I did that because I just wanted to get those QR codes on there,
so that you could start using them.
Because I think the QR code is the most important part,
because it pulls you up immediately to this,
I call it a data card.
So that's another way that you can quickly find a piano and pull it up,
is the QR code that's on the tag.
We haven't yet put them on the showroom pianos, that'll be shortly.
Let's look at a shop tag real fast.
I might not follow this very well,
because I can't see without my glasses.
So I skipped stuff,
you guys tell me what else I should talk about.
But the very, let's see,
where is the shop tag?
Towards the bottom of the piano's data card is a button to the shop tag.
So if you're working on a piano and you see that the shop tag is just
completely garbage and you know how it could be updated or improved,
then it would be helpful if you write on it,
what it actually should say,
like in this area that says scope of work.
See if I can, this says scope of work right there.
So serial number here,
this is the data that's not going to change about the piano,
just like it's generic information.
Then this scope of work section is where,
see this one doesn't have a track,
and I'll tell you in a minute what track is.
Then it has phase, and then it goes through what we refer to as concurrent work.
That's a new term. Track and
concurrent work and phase are new terms that we're going to be implementing.
But this scope of work basically says,
what did Brigham sell and promise to the client?
That's not going to change over the course.
It's like, what are we here to do on this piano?
Then you can use the QR code to scan for updates.
This entire list of items is all the things that are constantly changing,
and that's why they're not on the tag,
they're on the list to go to the QR code to see what it is currently.
That's all of the concurrent work items,
the queue, the map, all those things.
Media, we'll talk more about those.
But for example, let me tell you what these are.
Track. Track means, what's the big umbrella thing that was sold to this person?
So it could be rebuild, refurbish, hybrid.
It's got to be one of those.
Then it could also be refinishing is another track category,
and it could also be player restoration,
or QRS, or silent play technology.
So every piano has to have at least one track.
Most will have at least two because we refinish most,
and some might have even three.
So each one of those tracks has a list of phases that it goes through.
So by identifying the track,
and Melissa and Brigham will do this,
and then we identify the track,
and then it will auto-feed the collection of phases.
The phases are the work you're used to doing.
Let's see. I'll pull it up in just a minute when we go through the data card.
But it's like tear down, cap,
DHRT, restringing, QC.
Those are the phases that it will go through.
Concurrent work is all the other stuff that happens on the side while the phases are happening.
The things that happen concurrently are,
as you might be working on the action,
or the ribs, or the soundboard,
while Marcelo is working on the keytops.
So those are happening concurrently.
So the concurrent items are keytops,
base strings, plating, the plate that goes to Curtis,
maybe some other things,
but phases, concurrent tasks. Make sense?
Okay. Then these are the refinishing levels.
You want to, is Marcelo here?
He's not here. Okay. That's a good thing we're recording.
So you want to check these notes though.
We don't have it programmed yet,
but we're going to make it so that these notes go with the task.
So when Marcelo gets his assignment to do the keytops of this piano,
the notes that are written here for the keys should be in his notes.
If it's like keep the eyebrows,
or if there's a special note on plating,
then the plating note would be here,
and hopefully when you go to click on concurrent task,
hopefully that note would be there too.
We're going to make it hopefully that way.
Okay. So that's the tag.
The other way to find your piano.
Okay. Just a little detail on your phone and on a Chromebook.
Let's see if this will work for me.
This data card, theoretically.
Let's see. You see first floor and second floor up here.
Most of the pianos you guys are working on are first floor.
So let's go to, and see this button down here?
These are your sizing buttons.
This one returns it to full screen for whatever screen you're on.
This makes it bigger and smaller.
Once you make it bigger, then you can.
I can't really do it on this computer,
but on your phone,
you can move it, drag and drop it.
I don't know why it's not doing it on this.
It usually does, but I'll set it to the regular size.
Go back to first floor of the shop,
and let's pick a piano.
Let's go to this Steinway B. Okay.
There we go. See a little arrow?
I wanted this feature.
It just makes me so happy that it can do it.
It's just a tiny thing, but it just makes me so happy.
Look, you can resize your screen.
Isn't that great? Literally, anything you wanted to do.
Just tell us what your best ideas are.
Then on rare occasion,
it might say it's a grand, but it's really an upright.
That's what guides these little icons.
Yeah, this is a grand.
If it's actually an upright,
then you can just click this button and it'll change it to an upright.
See these red bars?
Those are all the section headers in the data cards.
They are expandable and retractable.
Thank you. Whatever you set yours as,
it will set all the pianos to that and it will remember it for your settings.
If you always want to open,
but the admin closed,
then it'll save that for you.
Okay. So we know how to find a piano.
Do we cover all of them? Then reading the map icons.
This is an important button down here.
I'll close this one out for now.
The legend, it's hidden unless it's there.
You see the legend? Can you see around me?
It's on the bottom. You see it over there?
Legend. You see it?
If you pop that open,
if you forget what different colors are,
because we have just gone wild and crazy with symbols and colors,
and eventually you won't need the legend, you'll just know them.
But at first, you'd be like,
what is the Ghostbuster sign?
Oh, I didn't add the Ghostbuster sign.
That's the newest one. Melissa had this idea.
I don't know why I didn't add it to the legend.
But if I wasn't teaching right now,
I would go to my phone, hit the idea button,
take a screenshot of this,
and submit it to myself,
and say the Ghostbuster sign isn't showing in the legend. Add it.
So I'll just tell you what the Ghostbuster sign is.
It's a circle with a line through it.
If you see a piano like that,
let's see if I think I know where one is.
I'll show you. Maybe I won't.
Well, when you see one like that,
if you try and open it, it means don't work on this piano.
Isn't that a good sign for that?
Oh, it has a Ghostbuster sign. Look at that.
So when you see the Ghostbuster sign,
it's going to bring up this big yellow bar.
It means it's pre-queue.
It's not yet in the queue,
but it's here in the building because they've said they want us to do it.
But they haven't paid their $1,000 to get in a queue.
We got a little problems in the past where people say they want it done,
but then they don't pay their money,
and then they never pay, and we've already torn it apart.
So we want to be careful that if they haven't paid
at least $1,000 to put money where their desires are,
and we don't want somebody tearing into it thinking they're doing
a great job getting the next piano started, and then we're in trouble.
So that's what the, and mine hasn't approved for queue because I'm an owner.
There's owner and managers and admins will have this approve for queue button.
There are some different features that have different permissions.
So if you ever wonder why maybe managers are
working on theirs and they're trying to train somebody to just hit this button,
it might just be on yours and it might not be on everyone's.
So there are a few features that are
position limited and approved for the queue. It's one of those.
So that's the Ghostbuster sign.
Okay. I'm not going to go over all the colors because they're self-explanatory.
You can learn those as you go.
The media icons needs photos and the video that's for Brigham and the admins.
One thing you probably don't need to know about,
but I'll just tell you because it's kind of fun.
The bench color is the,
obviously, there's grander upright icons,
and then the gray BLP owns versus the black client or consigned.
That's the bench color.
So if it's fully black,
there's actually a black bench there, you just can't see it.
That means that it's a client owned.
If it's a black upright with a gray bench,
it means it's a BLP owned one,
we're fixing up to sell it.
Sometimes it's helpful to know if it's client owned or store owned.
Then the codes you'll most be interested in are these.
Let me tell you how these work.
This was Brigham's idea, his brainchild.
If you don't like it, you can tell him,
come up with a better idea.
See how this one says 13.E?
We'll pull this up at the same time.
So 13.E, the E is for exit.
So originally, we were just going to have a number on top of
the pianos that identified what its phase is.
But Brigham was like, I can't remember the numbers.
So give me a hint.
With one extra letter, he can remember them.
So 6R, the R is for restringing.
So that's our little code.
So 3C is for cap.
It means that's the phase it's currently on.
Then there are a few extras at the bottom.
In the queue, if it's in a queue,
it's most likely in the parking lot on the map,
and it probably will say like Q17.
So Q17 means it's 17th in the queue.
Once it's in progress,
it's no longer going to show its queue number,
it's going to show its phase number.
But if you want to know what queue number a piano is,
but it's showing its phase number,
you just have to click into the card and then go look in
its location section and then you can find its queue number.
So this Steinway, which can't show everything on the icon.
So we prioritize the phase number if it's in progress.
So this one, it shows the map number and the queue number.
This one's 15 out of,
we currently have 66 pianos in the queue.
If you want to change the number,
if you are moving it,
there's a variety of ways you can change the map number.
You can't change queue numbers,
but you can change map numbers and you can change cabinetry.
Well, we'll get to that in just a second.
Then there's also a cabinetry history and a location history.
So on some occasions,
it might be helpful to know like this piano is here now,
but where was it?
What three spots was it?
Because I need to go look for a piece and it's missing,
and maybe it's in one of those locations where it was.
Or the cabinetry, if it got moved around a different shelves,
maybe a missing piece we could hunt in location histories.
Okay. So I was,
one more detail on the legend.
Okay. So the queue number is queue and the number paused means,
paused means it's in the queue and work has started,
but maybe there's a problem or waiting on a part or they've stopped paying,
or for some reason that work needs to pause,
even though it's mid queue.
So paused is different from haven't started yet.
Okay. Paused is also different from we're waiting on something.
Paused is like for some reason we're not moving ahead.
Whereas, there's three waitings on.
Waiting on means we wish it wasn't on hold or paused,
but we're waiting on something.
We're either waiting on Curtis Harper for the plate,
we're waiting on Brigham because maybe it needs
some special innovation or printing or CNC or I don't know,
something on Brigham, or we're waiting on other,
which is the whole catch-all category for everything else.
Okay. Then, yeah.
So what's the difference between paused and waiting on other?
Waiting on other means there's
some reason why maybe it's a base string got done wrong,
and so we're waiting on the new base string to
arise because an error was made.
So we're just waiting on something to move ahead,
and we're hoping it's going to happen as soon as possible.
Whereas, paused means maybe they're not paying right now,
or grandma died,
so the family's trying to figure out what to do with that piano,
because actually nobody wants it, and she thought they did.
Yeah. Paused is like,
you'll probably never know why it's paused,
but Brigham just hit the pause button for some random reason.
Whereas, waiting on is usually like a technical shop.
We're waiting on something,
and we just can't move ahead until that thing's done.
There's another term, which is similar,
but different, that you'll more be involved with,
but you might hear Mark talking about,
which is bottlenecks.
Bottlenecks is also something that causes pauses and waiting,
but a bottleneck is when
concurrent tasks are holding up the next phase.
Or possibly, it might be a bottleneck because there's only two technicians who
know how to do this specialty rib repair,
but they're already on pianos that are higher up in the queue,
and so that's a bottleneck.
That's a scheduling bottleneck.
Lots of variations of the same idea, right?
Okay. Any questions on the legend or move ahead with that?
Okay. That was a legend.
Okay. What's next? Did we get all the map icons?
Okay. Let's go through the piano card then.
Tell me if I missed anything on those notes that I can't see.
Let's pick a piano,
and how about 59?
Good piano? The Lester Grand?
Okay. Starting at the top,
I'm going to minimize all of the sections,
and we're just going to go through them one by one, okay?
All right. So, we already talked about the top.
This color up here, new,
is from the legend.
Okay. The work clock, did I?
This is where I think starting after this meeting,
whatever piano you're working on,
you can search for serial number,
use a QR code, or go to the data card,
and the first thing you can do is you can clock into that piano.
So, after this meeting, instead of using
I solved clock in and out of pianos,
start using the map,
and where you clock in and out of them is here.
You can't click on the clock in though
until you select the work you're doing.
So, select whatever task you're doing,
and if it's not there,
then all the way at the bottom, it says other,
and then in this spot,
you only have to write in what you're doing on this piano if you select other.
Otherwise, just select the work category,
and then your green button will come alive,
and you can clock in.
And then I think once you're clocked in, does it show it?
Can you also search that in the search bar too?
To clock in?
Yes.
Yes, the search bar will bring up this data card,
and then inside the data card in the first category,
the work clock, is where you'll clock in.
And then once you clock in,
does it show you a clock out button, I think,
and a timer?
So, it'll start a timer,
and it'll give you a clock out button.
So, if you move to a different piano,
same thing as iSolved.
And then starting September 1st,
there will be a replacement for iSolved,
just your full-time, your payroll clock in,
like when you arrive and when you leave.
That will be available here instead of iSolved starting September 1st,
and I'll show you where that is after we do the data card.
There's another feature we just added.
It's called My Dashboard.
It's in this hamburger drop-down menu.
We'll do that next.
Okay, so that's where you clock in and out of pianos.
Locations, we kind of already went over.
That's the map cue spot.
Okay, maybe we should talk about the cabinetry.
The cabinetry, you can add two ways.
You can either just add it right here,
or you can, if you're actually standing in the cabin,
we got to go to the second floor now.
Second floor tab, this is the cabinetry room.
And our brilliant system is just a web app version of your whiteboards.
So I think for now,
we should probably keep doing the whiteboards and do the app.
And maybe at some point,
someone will decide, okay, this is working,
everybody's doing it, it's accurate,
and we're all trained and we're all using our phones or the Chromebooks.
We don't need to have a double system anymore.
But until we're like, it's just flawless,
we should probably keep doing both.
So you can do it in the data card,
or you can open up whichever shelf you're on, say shelf seven.
And so this one has three boards you can choose from.
So if you want to add a piano to the unit seven on the left side
at the floor level, C floor,
you would click that button
and you just type in your serial number
and it'll bring in all the information for the piano.
Okay?
So I think it's self-explanatory,
but if you were gonna put it in the data card,
in the cabinetry box,
and the way you would, like the code would be,
if you were gonna put it on this spot right here,
it would be 3LF,
three for the unit, then L or R for left or right.
And then the third thing is either gonna be F for floor,
one for first shelf, two for second shelf,
three for a third shelf, or T for top shelf.
Okay?
Does that code make sense?
If you are actually taking up the whole floor,
cause you have so much cabinetry,
you're putting it on both spots,
then your code would be 3LRF.
Yeah?
Okay.
Okay, so that is the cabinetry.
And now I lost my piano, so let's pick a new one.
Let's pick this piano.
Let's see what it looks like.
Okay, see how it saved my locations?
I think that's, I think we covered everything for the,
oh, I guess you can change the queue number.
Just don't.
Maybe I'll, I gotta change the features on that.
I gotta change the permissions on that.
So if I was on my own phone, not doing print station,
I would take a screenshot, click on the light bulb,
and click on edit, upload the screenshot,
and say add permissions to the changing of the queue.
Okay, and then I can minimize this section.
Shot progress is the one I think you guys will use the most.
This, hopefully by the time a piano arrives in your site,
the track is already set.
But for now, you can add a track if it's not set.
You just click on it.
And then similarly with the keys, that should be set,
but click for that.
Shop phase.
As of right now, you can just click to the next phase
if you complete, if you're working on CAP and you finish it,
then you can click to the next phase.
But shortly, once we test it and make sure
that everybody's progress photos are working,
it's gonna give you a little pop-up.
If you try and move phases,
you're gonna be required to take a photo,
a progress photo, and upload the progress photo
before you can click on the next phase.
And those go to the tech folder.
We have before, after, and tech folders.
And then we're also using those photos.
It's automating a report to the client
based on what's been finished, and here's a photo.
For today, since that's not yet automated,
I think one of the things on the back of your sheet
that says test this out today,
if after this meeting, you could all take a photo
of whatever piano you're working on.
I think it's in the media section.
I think in the media section, yeah,
there's add progress photo.
So you can click on add progress photo.
It opens up your camera.
You click a photo and hit send, and it's that easy.
If you're not open here, you can use the QR code.
QR code, scroll down to media, open that progress photo,
click a photo, hit send, and it sends it
to the tech folder, okay?
Let's see, we were back on shop phase.
We already went over those.
When you hit delivered,
it should remove the piano from the map.
So if a piano's already been delivered,
but you still see it at the store,
that would be a light bulb to send a edit fix
that that's not working.
I'm not sure if we're gonna keep these done numbers or not.
Ideally, what this is gonna do is,
if you've said I'm done with phase four,
then the phases in front of it should be also done.
But you can click those.
I don't know that they're useful.
We might remove those.
That's another thing.
You know what's like general software?
You just have to have all the features
even if you only use 20% of them
because it doesn't quite fit your business.
That's not the case here.
So if we find over time, like for example,
we're not using this feature,
then that could be an idea button, a screenshot,
submit it, and we should get rid of it
if we're not using it.
And so we wanna keep,
we wanna make sure that this software
is just like 100% awesome and no fluff,
wasting our time or eyeballs.
And then there's the concurrent tasks.
This section is under construction.
It's not really ready yet.
But we decided to roll this out anyway
so you can start using the features that are.
So this needs work.
But the idea of what this is gonna be
is there will be like, for decal ordering,
it'll have a spot for the decal has been ordered
or received and same with plating.
It's been, you'll be able to see
where is this piano on, like this plate with Curtis.
We don't know if this plate is in the piano
at Curtis's shop or back in the rack or in the piano.
But shortly, we'll be able to just go to the data card
and we'll just know what is happening,
like keys, key tops.
Are they ready?
Are they in the cabinetry room?
Are they at Marcello's?
Are they done?
Are they in the piano?
We're just gonna know that
because the concurrent work will show that.
It's not quite ready yet.
Okay, the tech.
So that's the concurrent work list.
The tech reports history.
This had a glitch.
Let's see if it's working.
This is for the 1917 Steinway B.
Theoretically, it should open up.
All the reports of anything that's,
every report that's ever included this piano.
So if you're working on it or you're doing a QC
and you see that, oh my gosh,
whoever did this soundboard built the cracks wrong
and they need training or I don't know, some example.
If for some reason, something comes up
and you wonder who worked on what or what happened
or you can click on the technician reports
and you can use control F to look what you're searching for.
Every Friday report that's ever been submitted
for that piano, you now have access to since 2011.
Yeah, pretty cool, huh?
And then, okay, media section is next.
Mostly this is the admins in Brigham
but the progress photo is there
and we'll move that to a more convenient location too.
Paperwork, there's a little bit of overlap.
We might redesign this paperwork section.
Everybody stand up and stretch while I drink
because I'm putting you all to sleep.
I'm not a presenter.
Stand up and stretch, I'm gonna drink
and then I'll, I have ADHD.
You don't have to admit it
but anybody else in the room who has ADHD,
maybe take a walk, it's really stretch.
Good moving your body, resets your brain.
And you can even stay standing if you want, if that helps
or sit down, here we go again.
Paperwork is this stuff for concurrent work.
Right now, we're actually doing it on paper
like you showed the paper forms.
Glad you discovered that.
I didn't know there was two options
but I'm gonna be working with Jacob
and we're gonna be digitizing that, making it in the,
we're gonna have less and less paper around here.
For a little while, we're gonna have paper
that we digitize and it'll be attached here.
So the QC worksheets will be,
you'll be able to access them here.
And then eventually over time,
like the whiteboards will go away.
Also the paper will go away
and everything will be done in the web app.
So instead of filling out your teardown sheets
and your base things and the plating worksheets on paper,
we're gonna be filling it out in the web app.
It's not ready yet, it's under construction
but that'll be coming.
And then if you're wondering about one of those things,
you'll be able to find the information
right now in the paperwork section
but later it might be in the concurrent work section.
Okay, that's what that is right now.
Then paperwork, admin.
I don't think you guys need to do anything
with the admin section so you can just have that closed.
And then the PianoLog.
This is kind of cool, you guys.
You never had access to the PianoLog before.
You pretty much do now, except this is wrong.
It's not, I'll have to fix that.
But basically what the PianoLog does is it,
the PianoLog is this spreadsheet that we have
that runs our whole business
and it has all the pianos from 2011 forward
and there's like 100 columns.
And anything that hasn't yet been brought in
in the sections above is brought in here
to the PianoLog section.
So you probably won't need to reference it
but if there's ever some detail and you're wondering,
can we find out about that?
You could look here.
But you probably won't need to use the PianoLog section.
But that's what it is.
And this opens up to the PianoLog
that's now a digitized web app
but you probably won't need that button either.
Okay, any questions on the piano data cards?
Maybe we'll move on to the next thing?
Okay, what's next?
Piano card, okay.
Somebody skim that and tell me if I missed anything
so I can only read the headers.
Suggestions, improvements.
I think we've pretty much covered the light bulb today.
Okay, let me tell you about that.
Oh, that's a good thing to differentiate.
Okay, thanks for pointing that out.
In the, what section is it?
I think it's,
there is,
okay, this is, what section is this?
Admin, in the admin section,
this is mostly for Brigham or the managers
to request something on a piano.
So if you hit this request button within the data card,
it's going to send a request
or put something on somebody's calendar
or it's gonna send,
it's gonna email someone, text someone,
put it on someone's calendar.
It's gonna do something.
But it's gonna attach the information
of that specific piano.
So if you want it to be attached to a specific piano,
then do it within the data card.
If you want it to be moved or tuned,
if it needs service means,
service means everything that's like a repair,
a squeaky pedal.
If it's, you know, there's a recital complaint
or if there's a client who you're helping in the showroom
and they say, did you know that this B here is not working?
Then you could go into that piano,
go down to the admin section,
click on request,
click on service,
and then assign it to one of these technicians
and then say, sticky key in the middle octave
and the pedal squeaks or whatever.
The time allotted, best guess.
And then you can either schedule their next open slot
or schedule ASAP if it's like an urgency.
Let's see, what were the other ones?
Request.
If you have a request you wanna send to the admins,
Curtis Harper is for like if there's touch up,
like sometimes when there's restringing.
Mostly though, I don't think most of the technicians
are gonna be making these requests.
These are gonna be more Brigham admin and manager requests.
Price change, priority scheduling, a Brigham task.
If you wanna give Brigham a task
and tell him to do something,
this is the way to do it.
And it puts something about this piano
on Brigham's to do list.
How do you like that?
That could be really useful actually.
You guys now have a way of assigning piano tasks to Brigham.
Oh, we haven't tested this yet,
but do you wanna explain the temp map spot?
It's pretty cool.
This was one of the manager's ideas.
There's a slot for every piano right on the map.
And sometimes the way things change out,
it's like, well, we need to put this piano here
for a week or three days.
You're just kind of squeezing it in.
You can create a temp spot through here
that's like, hey, great.
This will be here just for this week.
Next week it'll be gone when we're done with the normal one.
So it's not one of these permanently fixed spots,
but anyway, just to get enough of it,
we just have to put something somewhere.
So we have that spot there.
Yeah, we haven't tested this yet.
So hopefully it works.
And if doesn't, we'll use label.
Mark is a duplicate.
There's not really a great way
if you accidentally put a piano two spots
because you think it's not somewhere
and so you enter it in,
but then, or you tried to pull it up
and the serial number wrong.
This is here because it happens.
And so you enter it in, but then we have duplicate.
This is just the only way we can get rid of duplicates.
The only way to like make a duplicate
is we get serial number wrong.
And so you think it's not there,
but, and then if you add one.
And then the shop tag is editable.
You can edit right on this to print a new one.
It's probably better to,
you can write it here or you can write in pencil
and take it to admin and they can update it.
And then you just hit print.
And it just prints whatever you edit.
And it prints two per page.
So there's one on each side of the piano.
Okay, but there's also this.
So that's to request any of those things
for that specific piano.
But this is request at the top.
This means it's not specific to a piano.
It is like a request in general, okay?
So the request at the top is just in general.
Okay, maybe what's next?
We did the suggestion improvements.
We did text to the shop number, reports and the archive.
Okay, let's go over that.
Let's go over the menu, everything that's in the menu.
So the store map is the first tab.
My dashboard I just added yesterday.
So it's not very well developed.
But each of you, my bad, I'm a technician.
I'm gonna change this so that the admins say,
piano admins.
By the way, we have a new admin starting today.
Super excited that we found someone who's super awesome.
Susie went to advance her education in Korea.
And we found a new person who's super overqualified
for the position.
But she wants a life career change
where she works somewhere that's less stress
with nice people in a nice environment.
And we won the golden prize.
So Lisa is our new admin.
So be nice to her because she wants to work somewhere nice.
And we convinced her that we're all nice here.
She starts today.
She'll be 10 to two Monday through Friday
and every other Saturday.
Just a little fun side note.
Our three admins plus Ezi are now Lisa, Alisa and Melissa.
So you could call me Carlisa or something.
Yes, isn't that fun?
Okay, so your dashboard.
This is where you're gonna be able to clock in for your day.
And when you clock in to the piano,
see this off the clock, it'll show right there
what piano you're clocked into.
And this pay logics is what's gonna change
to like your clock in, clock out.
I haven't tested all these features.
So I don't, maybe don't dive into these yet.
Let me, because you might just get frustrated.
I'm gonna test, keep testing these features
with the managers.
And then maybe at the morning meetings,
they can update you like, okay, start using your calendar,
your week and your Friday report.
But don't yet, because you might just be frustrated.
And then I might have 12 people sending me
the same light bulbs, okay?
But soon, you're gonna be submitting your Friday report
from here instead of to the spreadsheet.
You'll be able to pull up your Google calendar
and you'll be able to see your week.
Okay?
For this week, should we still plan on doing
the Google Sheets and Google for our Friday reports?
Yeah, except I'll probably have you guys be testing it.
Okay.
Okay, some of the other, this pianos
just goes to the piano log,
which you probably shouldn't need, but it's there.
It goes to a web app version of that enormous spreadsheet.
The shop app, you can click there if you want to.
But, and Mark gave you links to both this app
and the shop app, but I just recently decided,
I haven't even told Mark yet,
but I think the shop app is going to become
just a manager app, because I think all the features
that are there for the technicians
will be able to put into your dashboard.
And it'll just be easier for you guys
to just be all in one app and not toggling between apps,
because we've created a whole monstrosity,
Frankenstein, of so many apps.
We got so excited with AI,
and it's just so much fun to create anything you want,
that I was like, a web app for this,
and yeah, and this, and that.
And, you know, some of them are awesome
and some of them are learning.
And we're just gonna keep you guys
all in one web app that's awesome.
And the shop app is gonna be a managerial Brigham app.
So, and everything you go to,
if you do wanna go there and just see
what kind of a mess I've made in all the rough drafts,
you can see like what's in progress.
But it's kind of the rough draft working station.
It's like nothing that's like really ready to go.
The move board is for the movers.
If you're curious, it brings in their calendar
and shows what moves are coming up.
This little icon that's the moving truck,
that means there's one piano move today.
So, if you are wondering what the movers are doing,
you can click on that or click on the move board.
Calendar, oh, that's the mover calendar.
We should probably take that off.
That's an example of it doesn't really need to be there.
So, we should get rid of that.
Reports, reports are more managerial also.
So, I'm not gonna go over all of these.
But maybe one report that might be helpful
for everybody is the shop queue.
Marcelo came and asked me the other day
as his scheduling wasn't quite right.
And he's like, what piano should I do the keys for next?
And a technician helped me find some keys
in the cabinetry room, three that weren't done.
And the way I figured out which one he should do next
is I looked them all up in the queue
and I told him, do these three next
and then I put them in queue order.
So, if you want to see the pianos in order,
then that report can be helpful.
So, the way you, the reports are expandable and retractable.
Yeah.
I would assume it's what's clicked in the thing right now.
So, if it's on DHRT, then somebody's working on DHRT.
Yeah, because that's how it is in the data card.
If it's showing the phases DHRT,
that means that's what somebody's working on right now.
So, if it's in the queue, but it's not assigned yet,
how do we know, like, oh, someone is done on a Wednesday,
we need to get them to the next piano.
How would we know where the ones
that are currently being worked on end
and where the ones that need to be worked on are at?
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
Well, like, give me an example.
Who needs work?
Maybe somebody needs work, their next cap job.
So, maybe you'd start at the top,
maybe you'd start at the top of the queue and say,
well, we have to find a piano that is cap or before, right?
So, these are all DHRT is beyond.
It's already at its first tuning.
It's at chip tuning.
It's ready to exit.
That one's waiting on Brigham.
This one's already in cap and that one's waiting.
So, you got to keep going down.
That one's in refinishing.
We should have chose, like, we should have chose QC.
What's the next QC, right?
And then we'd, but I think you just scroll
until you find one that's.
Well, but then, does that show
if it's already assigned to somebody, though?
Like, on their calendar for the week?
No.
So, I'm working on the,
the, um, diagram square graph, right?
And it shows the cap right now.
Yeah.
If somebody needed a cap, they would look at the,
oh, well, I don't need to sign up
from your bar chart itself.
How do we see, like, who's already?
Let me say I don't know the answer to that
and it might not even be created.
So, that's, why don't you submit a light bulb
and say, let's figure out
how to answer that question quickly
and we can either make it in the Q report
or we can find another way to do it.
But that's, that's a great need identified.
Where we used to go, Brigham,
what should, what should Jake do next?
So, isn't this gonna be beautiful, you guys?
You know that piano log I told you about
that we've been keeping since 2011
that has, like, literally 100 columns
and thousands of pianos?
There was a time pre-piano log
when all that information was only in Brigham's head.
Could you imagine trying to be an admin
and work with Brigham
where all the information was locked in his brain?
We are trying to give you all the gift
of unlocking the information of the shop
so that one day, five years from now,
we're gonna be like, you remember pre-map
where we used to have to go ask Brigham
because all the information was, like, locked in his brain?
We're about to unlock the brain of Brigham
and all of you guys, everybody's gonna know
what everybody else is doing
and it's gonna be glorious.
It's a new era, you guys.
It's very exciting.
Information is powerful.
But I don't know the answer to that,
so let's figure it out.
Okay, any other shop reports
that would be useful to the masses?
I am gonna minimize this one.
Oh, and it has that share button and a print button,
so if you, you can text the reports
or print them if that's helpful.
What was your question?
Oh, yeah.
This one, I would say is in progress,
but we added filters to it.
So, for example, if Marcello wants to know
what key tops he should work on next,
you can filter for, so these are,
I don't know if these are right or not.
I think that AI decided what to put in this filter.
What's an, shoot, what's that?
Is that a concurrent task?
Okay, so we'll tidy this up,
but basically you can filter
for different concurrent tasks
and find maybe what's next.
Or you might filter for decals
and it'll pull up a list and show you
all the decals that are ordered versus arrived.
And so that'll be a useful report, too,
for those who are doing those tasks.
Then there's a lot of other,
most of these, the technicians,
the managers will be using.
There is one you might be interested about knowing.
The activity log just keeps,
everything you do is being watched and checked.
It's basically like the 1984 version of shop apps.
Everything is recorded, so when you're logged in,
it shows every click in detail, who's doing what.
So if we have any questions, you see?
Garrett, good job, look at that.
Garrett just did this, he moved piano.
So this, and this is also filterable.
So if you're wondering who did what or what action,
so you can filter the activity log for moves.
You can filter it and say,
who moved what pianos where in the last week?
Because Corbin just asked me this morning,
he said, I'm supposed to be tuning a piano here,
but it's not here, and it's not in the last three spots.
Where's the piano?
And I said, I don't know.
But after this meeting,
hopefully we're all gonna be updating our map spots,
and we'll all know where everything is.
And if we don't, we could go to the activity log
and filter for moves, and I don't know,
it would be another piece of the puzzle
to try and put things together.
Okay, media is mostly for admins, Brigham, shop, work.
Oh, this is just a curiosity.
Nobody's gonna need, actually Brigham is interested in this,
but you just can know about it for fun.
This is the current map of all the pianos
that are currently in the queue
of where they came from around the nation.
So this helps us to put together national road trips
or family vacations since mostly we only vacation
according to our business.
So you might hear about us soon going on a East Coast
RV piano delivery trip.
And so you might notice that whatever pianos these are,
Brigham might be really trying to hustle those
through the queue so that we can deliver them all together.
Or maybe he sends our boys on a California trip.
And so he's gonna be trying to hustle those through the queue
which is kind of interesting, isn't it?
Good job fixing pianos all around the nation.
Kind of fun.
I digress.
Okay, shop map, not much tab.
I'm like the queen of tabs, I always have too many tabs open.
Okay, I think we're through that.
And then what else?
Did we make it through everything?
Map icons, managed hands, okay.
We went through the menu.
Oh, there's one more useful thing.
There's a, yeah, for the map?
Oh yeah, let me show that.
And then I think we have a archive.
Where is that?
In the reports.
Sometimes, this is more an admin Brigham thing,
but sometimes, like maybe you find a part
with a serial number and it's like,
that serial number is not in the shop.
You now have access to the whole history of pianos,
but I can't remember where it is.
It's the archive.
There is an archive.
Waiting on?
Well, it's gonna show up here soon,
but you'll be able to search for a piano
and if it's already been delivered
or it's been, we did it five years ago
and in some corner of the building,
we find some part with that serial number,
then you'll now have access to it
because it's, I need to do a light bulb
and say, where's the archive report?
Delivered archive.
Where's that?
Top right menu.
Delivered archive?
Top right.
I don't have it.
Oh, let me tell you this.
I don't know if this is a thing or not,
but sometimes, you might submit a light bulb
and then you get a text back
or they tell you at the morning meeting,
like, this has been added.
Cool new feature.
And it's not, you don't have it.
It's not working for you.
This refresh button loads.
If you don't hit the refresh button
or sometimes you have to log out, log in
and I don't know if it's gonna pull it up for me now
if I had permissions, but let's see if it shows up.
Where?
Oh, there it is.
Thank you for that example.
I didn't even have that on my notes,
but if you're missing something
that somebody says is a feature and it should be there,
you can try reloading the URL, okay?
You have to, you do?
Maybe on your phone, but on my laptop,
I just have to hit the refresh circle.
So hopefully on the Chromebooks,
you just have to hit the refresh circle,
but maybe on your phones, you have to log in, log out.
Okay, so that was the reports in the archive.
Managers and admins only.
You guys can just skim those.
Don't really talk about that.
Hands-on practice.
Do these things now.
You can just, let's see, do we talk about all of them?
Scan a shot, move a test panel.
Oh, you wanted me to talk about the attic,
and then we talked about location history, progress photos.
I'm gonna talk about the attic and the parking lot,
and then unless there's any questions,
I think we covered the basics,
and there's gonna be so much more coming with this,
but I think we'll just give ongoing updates
at morning meetings, like here's the new feature.
This feature's live.
So-and-so had this idea.
Now it's live, and, okay?
But let me show you the, explain the attic.
Somebody ringing, or is that my phone?
Because my phone makes that noise.
Is it me?
Is that my bag making music?
It's nice.
Sorry, oh, it's Melissa.
Hi, Melissa.
Okay, no problem.
I got you.
Don't even worry about it.
Okay, but thanks for the update.
Okay, bye.
She's gonna be five minutes late.
We're training a new admin, so she's panicking,
but we'll be done.
Okay, last thing.
Let me find my store map,
and let's go to the second floor.
Got our cabinetry room.
Oh, let me tell you one more thing I just thought of.
There's probably so many things I'm forgetting,
but in the, in this room over here,
the original map didn't quite,
Brigham made this original map
like five years ago or something,
and we've stuffed more pianos in there that don't fit,
and so he solved that problem by,
now there's 211, 212, 213,
and then there's 213, ABCD, EFG,
and so if you're looking at these pianos,
and we did the same thing in the vestibule.
In an ideal world, the vestibule would be like
clean and simple with one grand here and five grand there,
but the reality is sometimes we stuff 20 uprights
in the vestibule when we're overloaded,
and there's sometimes four grand stuffed in the other side,
and so we added, on the little side,
we added whatever that number is in ABCD,
and then on the long side, there's .5s,
so we had to get creative,
and then this section here,
Brigham's office, we stuffed all the rental pianos,
they're like rented in people's houses,
if you're wondering why Brigham's office has so many,
ah, go away, why all those are there,
and, oh no, that's the recital hall,
and then Brigham's office, we have the finance pianos
and the Larson, the ones that are at our house
or are in the building for some reason.
Okay, in the attic, let me explain what the attic is,
because are there really pianos in the attic?
There's not actually pianos in the attic.
That's just a spot that we use to,
those are the, they get, the pianos get shot to the attic
if they need a spot assigned,
so if you physically go to a spot
and you're standing in front of a grand piano,
but on the map is a different piano,
if you, and you can definitely confirm this,
well, you're like standing at spot 89,
and this is a Highland Grand, it's not a powered upright,
so you wanna go to the map and type in the correct piano
that's actually in that physical spot,
and what the app, what the store map is gonna do
is the wrong piano is gonna be shot to the attic,
and so then the admin or managers
or if you know where the wrong piano is,
you can put it in the right spot
and it'll grab it from the attic
and put it in the right spot,
but oftentimes, you only know the right piano,
you don't know where the wrong piano is,
and so as soon as you put in the right piano,
the wrong one gets shot to the attic
until someone finds it and puts it in the right spot.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, so I would request,
we don't have a feature for catching you
for putting the wrong piano in the wrong spot,
but it would be helpful if you only put,
assign a piano to a spot,
if you're like, you're there,
you know it's like actually visibly in this spot,
like don't guess like,
oh, that piano is in spot 72 in the showroom,
so I'll put it there,
because if you're wrong,
it's gonna shoot pianos to the wrong spot, you know?
Okay, and then there's just a few weird ones too,
like digitals and stuff, but in general, that's it,
and in the parking lot, back to the first floor,
in the parking lot, these yellow pianos are coming soon,
so they all have queue numbers,
see, we've got queue seven,
I don't know why it's grayed out like that,
I don't really like that,
and it didn't used to be that way,
I'm gonna light bulb that so those aren't grayed out,
but all those yellow ones are coming soon,
they're in the queue, but they haven't arrived yet,
and then the out for service is typically just the ones
that are going to Salt Lake to have the QRS put in,
they're at another shop,
but they're still in the queue and in a phase, okay?
What else should I cover?
Did I miss anything or anybody have any questions?
Or do you wanna go just get started?
You can go start, you can do some hands-on practice,
take a photo, make sure that whatever piano
you're working on, use the QR code
or type in the serial number,
and make sure that whatever piano you're working on
is on the correct phase,
and in the right map spot, that would be most helpful.
Okay, yeah?
Okay, for signing in and out,
for right now, we're going to start signing in
to the piano on the web app?
Yeah, just starting today,
we're just signing in and out of pianos.
Like-
Do you still use iSolved?
For arrival and exit to the building,
we're gonna, no, stop,
you're gonna keep using iSolved
for arrival to the building and exit of the building,
but no longer for pianos, right?
So as of right this minute,
you're gonna clock in and out of your specific piano
in the new system, this door map,
but keep clocking in and out of iSolved for the day,
and we're gonna switch that over on September 1st.
Yeah, and we're gonna add that to your dashboard.
Right now, we're like clocked into miscellaneous.
So clock out of that, and then clock into, in iSolved,
clock out of miscellaneous in iSolved,
and then your next clock into your piano,
do in the store map.
And you clock in and out of pianos
in the specific data card,
but you're gonna be clocking on September 1st,
you're gonna be clocking in and out of your day
for payroll in your dashboard, my dashboard,
which is the first item in your hamburger menu.
What other questions do you have?
We got it.
Easy peasy.
Yeah.
For example, in the main shop right now,
it's just kind of crowded with grand pianos,
and they're not exactly in the nice and tight spots
in the map.
Yeah.
In this area.
Well, if there's four grands in this front area,
then they should be one of those numbers,
even if they're like, you know,
there's maybe three in a row and one other one,
there's four grands in that spot.
But if there's a fifth grand smashed into that spot,
then we need to use the temp spot feature.
And then, but that is not tested yet,
so we're gonna test that.
And then in general,
there's kind of like four pianos
for each two restoration lines.
If there's another one smashed in there,
if we add an upright to the ends or something,
and we're, you know, we try and avoid that,
but then we'd have to use a temp spot.
So I guess the answer is choose the spot
that's closest to it that's not already taken.
And if there's not one,
if it's been smashed in there,
then we have to create a temp spot.
Good question.
Yeah.
What?
Oh, yeah.
But that was more of a like a practice development thing.
And so we don't want you to use the team pin,
we want you to log in.
Log in with your Google.
The Google was kind of finicky.
And so we had a pin to just override the Google log in,
but we want you to use the Google log in,
because then you'll show up in the activity log.
Yeah, and we'll know who's doing what.
Oh, to save the stage.
It might be a permissions feature.
I might need to update the permissions.
Try Piano Man and see if it lets you do it.
But I'll get rid of that.
So that would be a helpful thing to screenshot and set it,
because I don't want you to have to do a pin
every time you do an update.
So try Piano Man, if that doesn't,
and then it'd be helpful if you send a screenshot of that
to the light bulb.
So the main, I'm glad you found that,
because I just want to reemphasize, this is brand new.
I'm not an AI or software expert,
but I'm getting pretty good at it.
But the main goal is to just try it out,
find all the glitches and problems.
If we find lots of glitches and problems,
that's super success.
And just submit ideas, too,
if you have your own little light bulb ideas.
And this is going to be years in the making,
so everything isn't going to be just perfect from the start.
Okay, so grateful for all your ideas and help and patience,
and hopefully it makes your jobs easier and better.
That's the hope.
Yeah?
What would it entail,
because we're using Homebase and Wi-Fi,
so do we need to clock into Pianos still?
Do you clock into Pianos now?
No.
Do we need to do that?
Oh, yeah.
Go ahead, you can keep using Homebase
till September 1st, and then you'll use the new system,
and you can start clocking in to Pianos today.
Okay.
All right, any other questions,
you can just ask me personally,
and, or text me, you've got my text.
And, thanks.
Yeah?
Will this eventually become a kind of
replace of the Friday reports?
Possibly, you mean like you won't even need
to submit a Friday report?
There's a good chance that, I don't know.
I don't know how good this will get and how accurate,
but yeah, I think it might,
because we're just going to have real-time data.
But there might still be, yeah, I haven't thought about that,
but I bet it will.
But for now, it's kind of like,
for now it's kind of like the whiteboard
in the cabinetry room,
where we're going to have both systems for a while.
So, soon we'll be doing your Friday report in the new app,
and then maybe eventually there will be no Friday reports.
So everything will just be updated in real-time.
And if you have a message for Brigham,
you'll just send it to Brigham's Tasks,
or send him a message, I don't know.
We'll see.
Okay, thanks everybody.
Okay.
Oh, oh, sorry.
You know what?
I will,
I think I can get a transcript of this,
it can translate to Spanish,
and then I can get a Spanish version of this.
Yeah, thanks.